const quizQuestions15en = [{
    question:"The inductance in the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["controls the behaviour of the voltage, mainly in the case of metal transfer by short circuits;",
    "controls the behaviour of the current, mainly in the case of metal transfer by short circuits;",
    "affects the behaviour of the current, especially in the case of spray metal transfer;",
    "controls the energy generated by the electric arc, especially in the case of spray metal transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The brown colour code on a tungsten electrode designates:",
    answers: ["pure tungsten electrode;",
    "zirconated tungsten electrode;",
    "1% thoriated tungsten electrode;",
    "1% lanthanated tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding to laser welding process for carbon steel, which is true?",
    answers: ["Due to its heat transfer capacity, high requirements on edge preparation are not necessary.",
    "Adequate joint preparation is essential to obtain a high-quality welding bead.",
    "Highly polished surfaces may increase heat transfer from keyhole to welding joint.",
    "Surface roughness may reduce welding penetration, once laser absorbance will become lower."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is true when it comes to basic equipment for each type of process?",
    answers: ["Optical resonators are equipment used to produce laser beams.",
    "For electron beam welding, vacuum working chambers are necessary to avoid heat losses.",
    "Due to its similarity, GTAW torches can be used in plasma arc welding process.",
    "Vortex concentrators are used to focus the laser beam into the workpiece surface."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which are the welding processes used in cladding?",
    answers: ["Process 111 supplied with direct current electrode positive.",
    "SAW with strip electrode supplied with direct current electrode negative.",
    "RSW with strip electrode supplied with direct current electrode negative.",
    "MIG/MAG welding with direct current electrode negative."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Using a robotic system for MIG/MAG welding usually:",
    answers: ["increases deposition rate;",
    "increases penetration;",
    "increases wire feed speed;",
    "reduces non-productive time."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the joining of ceramic materials, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Only ceramics of the same type are possible to join.",
    "Almost always involves filler materials used in brazing.",
    "It must involve a partial melting of one of the joining ceramic materials.",
    "Filler materials are not used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Plasma arc welding (PAW) process, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow and columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high arc voltage is the main factor in ensuring the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "Plasma arc welding demands tighter tolerances in the preparation and fixing of the joints than, e.g., in TIG process.",
    "A high arc voltage is one of the main factors for increasing the plasma jet speed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"On of the factors that governs the quality of a thermal spray deposited coating using powder is:",
    answers: ["powder particle density;",
    "substrate thickness;",
    "work position (flat, vertical, others);",
    "deposit density."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"On of the factors that governs the quality of a thermal spray deposited coating using powder is:",
    answers: ["powder particle density;",
    "powder particle size;",
    "substrate thickness;",
    "work position (flat, vertical, others);"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"On of the factors that governs the quality of a thermal spray deposited coating using powder is:",
    answers: ["powder particle density;",
    "substrate thickness;",
    "powder particle temperature;",
    "work position (flat, vertical, others);"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Less (than in welding): operating time, energy consumption, modification of metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (less residual stress problems).",
    "It makes it possible to perform any type of joint (butt, angle, lapping and others).",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding filler metals for brazing/soldering, mark the correct statement:",
    answers: ["Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is used for large gap joints and a long melting temperature range filler metal for small gap joints.",
    "Copper alloys (e.g., copper-zinc) are used in joining all ferrous and non-ferrous materials, in lap or butt joints, with different heating methods.",
    "The filler metal does not eliminate surface contamination, pre-cleaning is required (e.g., via a flux).",
    "The most suitable filler metal for soldering is lead."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true alternative, regarding the brazing/soldering processes:",
    answers: ["A protective atmosphere is never used.",
    "To ensure better wetting in brazing/soldering, the surface must be cleaned of oxides and heated.",
    "In brazing, the filler metal must always be heated until it melts, but there is no need for the base metal to be heated.",
    "Pickling fluxes or liquids are used in brazing to prevent corrosion of the workpiece after brazing."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding carbon arc cutting, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["the process uses a jet of inert gas to remove the molten metal;",
    "when cutting steel, the recommended polarity is the direct current electrode negative (DCEN);",
    "it implies risks of contamination of the base metal by carbon;",
    "the finishing of carbon arc gouging is better than plasma gouging."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In resistance spot welding, it is possible to measure the current level using the following device:",
    answers: ["Solenoid.",
    "Rogowski coil.",
    "Nikola Tesla ammeter.",
    "Nikola Tesla solenoid."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In resistance spot welding, it is possible to measure the current level using the following device:",
    answers: ["Solenoid.",
    "Toroid.",
    "Nikola Tesla ammeter.",
    "Nikola Tesla solenoid."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which defect is not typical for workpieces made by Additive Manufacturing?",
    answers: ["High surface roughness.",
    "Porosity.",
    "Cracking.",
    "Shrinkage."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When welding stainless steel pipes, the TIG welding process is usually used for the root pass. What is one of the reasons for this?",
    answers: ["To prevent slag and spatter from entering the pipe (if other welding processes were used).",
    "To ensure high penetration.",
    "The TIG process offers greater welding speeds in making root passes.",
    "To prevent magnetic arc blowing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When welding stainless steel pipes, the TIG welding process is usually used for the root pass. What is one of the reasons for this?",
    answers: ["To ensure high penetration.",
    "The TIG process offers greater welding speeds in making root passes.",
    "To prevent magnetic arc blowing.",
    "To obtain better control of heat input and therefore avoid both lack of fusion and perforation in root passes."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of welding processes into “fusion” and “solid state” welding, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["\"\"\"Solid State\"\" welding processes do not have as good a mechanical strength as those of \"\"fusion\"\" type and are applied only in joints of low responsibility.\"",
    "\"As there is, in general, no fusion between the parts, \"\"solid state\"\" processes have advantages in terms of minimizing tensions and deformations of the joint.\"",
    "\"TIG welding is considered a \"\"solid state\"\" process, as the tungsten electrode does not undergo fusion.\"",
    "\"Usually, \"\"solid state\"\" welding processes are slower compared to \"\"fusion\"\" welding processes.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The laser (LBW) and electron beam (EBW) welding processes are characterized by a following characteristic:",
    answers: ["They tolerate large root gaps between sheets to be welded.",
    "They are easily handled during manual welding.",
    "They are low heat input processes.",
    "They use the most expensive filler metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"It is considered to be a “good practice” in a stress relieving heat treatment:",
    answers: ["To heat and cool the part/component slowly so a high temperature gradient is not created;",
    "To remove jigs and fasteners before this heat treatment is applied, to avoid distortion;",
    "To heat the part/component quickly in order to do not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "To heat the part/component slowly so as not to harden the material."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Charpy test, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The energy absorbed to fracture the specimen is a measure of the toughness of the material at the test temperature;",
    "The temperature at which the test must be applied is 20 oC;",
    "The results obtained according to the ASTM E23 standard procedure are the same as those obtained when performing the same test according to the DIN EM (ISO) standard, despite both use different forms of notching;",
    "The temperature at which the test is applied does not affect the results as long as it is below 0 oC."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Charpy test, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The impact resistance of the material is given by the difference between the potential energies of the pendulum at the starting position and at the maximum height reached after the fracture of the specimen;",
    "The temperature at which the test must be applied is 20 oC;",
    "One of the disadvantages of the Charpy test is that the energy absorbed depends on the weight of the pendulum and on the length of the pendulum's arm;",
    "Materials brittle at room temperature have higher energy absorbed in the test at cryogenic temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Charpy test, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The lower the temperature of the specimen, the lower the energy absorbed;",
    "The temperature at which the test must be applied is 20 oC;",
    "One of the disadvantages of the Charpy test is that the energy absorbed depends on the weight of the pendulum and on the length of the pendulum's arm;",
    "Materials brittle at room temperature have higher energy absorbed in the test at cryogenic temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding mechanical testing:",
    answers: ["Mechanical testing of material properties does not need to be conducted according to standards, as it reveals intrinsic properties of materials;",
    "The samples used in tensile tests are discarded, whereas those of bending tests can be straightened and tested again;",
    "After taking a sample for mechanical testing, that welded joint can be repaired in order do not discard it;",
    "Mechanical tests are generally destructive, as they cause the material to break or become unusable (example: traction, bending, torsion, fatigue, impact, ...)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding mechanical testing:",
    answers: ["Mechanical testing of material properties does not need to be conducted according to standards, as it reveals intrinsic properties of materials;",
    "The samples used in tensile tests are discarded, whereas those of bending tests can be straightened and tested again;",
    "After taking a sample for mechanical testing, that welded joint can be repaired in order do not discard it;",
    "Mechanical tests are always performed by applying mechanical stresses (traction, bending, shear) to a material sample."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding mechanical testing:",
    answers: ["Mechanical testing of material properties does not need to be conducted according to standards, as it reveals intrinsic properties of materials;",
    "The samples used in tensile tests are discarded, whereas those of bending tests can be straightened and tested again;",
    "After taking a sample for mechanical testing, that welded joint can be repaired in order do not discard it;",
    "The type of test that must be performed depends on the product (following standards), but it is up to the user to choose the standard according to the purpose of use of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct statement regarding hardness:",
    answers: ["Brinell testing is the best method for assessing the hardness of the coarse-grained region of a HAZ;",
    "To measure the hardness of a hard coating, the Vickers micro-hardness test must be used;",
    "Hardness tests consist of applying a determined load through an indenter of known geometry and measuring the dimension of the impression produced on the surface of the specimen;",
    "For low-carbon and low-alloy steels, the higher the tensile strength limit, the lower its hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct statement regarding hardness:",
    answers: ["Brinell testing is the best method for assessing the hardness of the coarse-grained region of a HAZ;",
    "To measure the hardness of a hard coating, the Vickers micro-hardness test must be used;",
    "For low-carbon and low-alloy steels, the higher the tensile strength limit, the greater its hardness;",
    "For low-carbon and low-alloy steels, the higher the tensile strength limit, the lower its hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Indicate the correct statement regarding the phenomena that occur during the tensile test.",
    answers: ["The point at which plastic deformation begins is called the failure start point.",
    "Elastic deformation is reversible and occurs by increasing or decreasing the interatomic distances in the material.",
    "The permanent (plastic) elongation and the reduction of the section before the fracture are conventional measures of material toughness.",
    "The material in the region of plastic deformation no longer shows any elastic deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following steels are used for cryogenic applications?",
    answers: ["Ni alloyed or austenitic stainless steels",
    "Low alloy Cr-Mo steels.",
    "Low alloy C-Mn steels.",
    "Rimmed steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weldability of thick cast iron gives least problems when using:",
    answers: ["ferritic grey cast iron;",
    "ordinary grey cast iron;",
    "white cast iron;",
    "ferritic nodular cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In addition to variations of the properties due to the shape of the specimens, the rate of loading will also affect the results in tensile testing. As the testing speed is increased:",
    answers: ["tensile strength increases and ductility decreases;",
    "tensile strength decreases and ductility increases;",
    "both tensile strength and ductility increase;",
    "both tensile strength and ductility decrease."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Aluminium alloys Al-Mg belong to material group (ISO/TR 15608):",
    answers: ["22",
    "32",
    "42",
    "52"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Observing the service temperature, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["at cryogenic temperatures, common carbon steels should be used, as they are more ductile;",
    "a welded joint must operate at a temperature higher than its ductile/brittle transition temperature;",
    "in general, mechanical strength decreases and ductility increases with reduction in temperature;",
    "generally, only metals and alloys with a BCC-type crystal structure are used for low temperature service."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following would be used to give an approximate tensile strength of a steel item?",
    answers: ["Charpy impact test (the yield strength in MPa ≈ 3 times the impact value expressed in J).",
    "Izod impact test (the yield strength in MPa ≈ 10 times the impact value expressed in J).",
    "Fatigue test (the yield strength in MPa ≈ 1/75 of number of cycles).",
    "Hardness test (the yield strength in MPa ≈ 1/3 of hardness value expressed in MPa)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if a thermomechanically treated high yield strength steel is NOT preheated to a sufficiently high temperature?",
    answers: ["Grains in the heat affected zone grow.",
    "A lack of penetration may occur.",
    "Too much ferrite will be formed.",
    "A risk of cold cracking increases."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if a thermomechanically treated high yield strength steel is preheated to an excessive temperature?",
    answers: ["As opposite to expected, a brittle structure may be formed with a risk of cold cracking.",
    "An excessive penetration may occur.",
    "Too much ferrite will be formed.",
    "A decrease of the yield strength can be observed (softening)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if a ferritic stainless steel is preheated to an excessive temperature?",
    answers: ["A decrease of the yield strength can be observed (softening).",
    "An excessive penetration may occur.",
    "Too much austenite will be formed.",
    "Undesired granular growth may occur, giving rise to embrittlement."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if a duplex stainless steel is preheated to an excessive temperature?",
    answers: ["Undesired granular growth may occur, giving rise to embrittlement.",
    "An excessive penetration may occur.",
    "Too much ferrite will be formed, which has a negative effect on the corrosion resistance.",
    "A decrease of the yield strength can be observed (softening)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if metals, that have obtained their mechanical properties by means of precipitation hardening, are preheated to an excessive temperature?",
    answers: ["The precipitates can grow, which leads to embrittlement.",
    "An excessive penetration may occur.",
    "Too much ferrite will be formed.",
    "A decrease of the yield strength can be observed (softening)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What can be determined on the basis of the time t8/5 and a CCT diagram for unalloyed steel?",
    answers: ["Recommended heat input.",
    "Recommended preheat temperature.",
    "Expected hardness in the heat affected zone.",
    "Steel Ferrite Number"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"If two dissimilar materials are to be joined by welding and preheat is required, which preheat temperature to be used? ",
    answers: ["That of the material with the higher preheat specified.",
    "That of the material with the lower preheat specified.",
    "Equal to the mean value of the highest and the lowest preheat temperatures.",
    "Each joint component should be preheated according to its specified temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In welding of high-strength steels a following recommendation is taken into account:",
    answers: ["high-strength steels should not be preheated;",
    "welding is carried out with controlled heat input and the interpass temperature is maintained;",
    "austenitic filler materials are used;",
    "preheat temperature is by 100 ºC higher than for unalloyed steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What welding conditions and precautions should be used for manual metal arc welding of a high strength steel?",
    answers: ["Use of low welding speeds.",
    "Use of higher preheat temperatures.",
    "Avoid preheating (because at low heat inputs, the weld metal exhibits poor toughness, while at higher heat inputs, weld metal has poor strength).",
    "Welded joints should be NDT inspected at least 48 hours after welding, in order to check for cold cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is the PWHT Tempering at Elevated Temperatures (600 - 750 °C) normally applied to Cr-Mo steel welds?",
    answers: ["To reduce the residual stresses and thus preventing the hydrogen cracks;",
    "To give the time to hydrogen to “bake out” of the material and thus preventing the cold cracking;",
    "To produce specific metallurgical structures in order to improve the creep resistance.",
    "Primarily to improve the creep resistance by reducing the residual welding stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which heat treatment would you recommend for Cr-Mo steel welds, in order to get optimum creep resistance properties?",
    answers: ["Precipitation hardening.",
    "Tempering at elevated temperatures (600 - 750 °C).",
    "Quenching.",
    "Normalizing."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following problems can mainly occur during or after welding of Cr-Mo steel?",
    answers: ["Hot cracking.",
    "Cold cracking.",
    "Sensitization in the weld metal.",
    "Sensitization in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which action is most effective in preventing carbide precipitation when welding austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Minimizing iron in the base metal.",
    "Minimizing chromium in the base metal.",
    "Minimizing nickel in the base metal.",
    "Minimizing the heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding thermomechanically treated steel of thickness above 15 mm you should use:",
    answers: ["high heat input without preheating;",
    "high heat input with preheating;",
    "low heat input without preheating;",
    "low heat input with preheating."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["the values of impact toughness of the welded material are lower than 27J;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Titanium:",
    answers: ["gas protection must be efficient for all area of the weldment heated above 500°C;",
    "welding is possible only in the flat position (due to a high fluidity of the welding pool);",
    "only basic type low hydrogen covered electrode shall be used (when MMA/SMAW is applied);",
    "the shielding gas flow must be at least twice as high as in the case of welding aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cryogenic application temperatures are less than:",
    answers: ["- 35 °C;",
    "- 45 °C;",
    "- 55 °C;",
    "- 65 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A fracture failure involves the nucleation of one or more cracks and an initially stable and later unstable growth of them. Regarding these stages, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The lower the tenacity of the material, the longer the stages of stable growth tend to be;",
    "In analysing a fracture surface, it is generally more important to locate the region where unstable fracture propagation has occurred;",
    "The growth of internal stresses is one of the typical stages in the fracture process;",
    "Stable growth can be maintained by the fatigue phenomenon, while unstable growth cannot."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A fracture failure involves the nucleation of one or more cracks and an initially stable and later unstable growth of them. Regarding these steps, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The lower the tenacity of the material, the longer the stages of stable growth tend to be;",
    "In analysing a fracture surface, it is generally more important to locate the region where unstable fracture propagation has occurred;",
    "The growth of internal stresses is one of the typical stages in the fracture process;",
    "Crack nucleation is facilitated by stress concentrators."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["the welded joint has some weld defects;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["some types of stress concentrators are generated;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["there are sudden transitions in the shape and thickness of the joint components;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["butt joints are replaced with corner joints;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["there is misalignment in butt joints;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["there is partial penetration in the welds;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["the welded plate thickness is increased;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["high residual stresses are generated;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["the welded joint is stress relieved;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["the joint has sharp edges and corners;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture of the welded joint of Ni cryogen steels is higher when:",
    answers: ["applied loads are very concentrated;",
    "the welded plate thickness is reduced;",
    "the heat input is low;",
    "the welded joint has not been stress relieved."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement about Vickers hardness tests:",
    answers: ["The biggest difference between the Vickers hardness and Vickers microhardness tests is that the indenter of the former is diamond and that of the latter is ruby, to allow indentation under low loads.",
    "The biggest similarity between Vickers hardness and Vickers microhardness tests is that the indenters are made of diamond and the hardness measurement is done by measuring the indentations.",
    "The Vickers test determines the average hardness of a region, so it is the most suitable for measuring the HAZ hardness;",
    "The Vickers microhardness test allows determining the sub-surface hardness of Weld Overlay (deposition of filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the phenomenon of fatigue:",
    answers: ["Fatigue occurs on brittle materials only (there is no evidence of plastic deformation).",
    "The propagation direction of the fatigue crack coincides with the direction of application of the tensile stress that opens it.",
    "The unstable crack propagation is further accelerated by the assistance of fatigue (cyclic loading).",
    "Fatigue occurs even when a component is subjected to stresses within the elastic regime (that is, to stresses below the yield limit)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the phenomenon of fatigue:",
    answers: ["Fatigue occurs on brittle materials only (there is no evidence of plastic deformation).",
    "The propagation direction of the fatigue crack coincides with the direction of application of the tensile stress that opens it.",
    "The unstable crack propagation is further accelerated by the assistance of fatigue (cyclic loading).",
    "The fatigue limit is defined as the level of stress amplitude below which no fatigue fracture is observed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the phenomenon of fatigue:",
    answers: ["Fatigue occurs on brittle materials only (there is no evidence of plastic deformation).",
    "The propagation direction of the fatigue crack coincides with the direction of application of the tensile stress that opens it.",
    "The unstable crack propagation is further accelerated by the assistance of fatigue (cyclic loading).",
    "The fatigue strength of materials is defined as the ability to withstand cyclical stresses without breaking with time."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the phenomenon of fatigue:",
    answers: ["Fatigue occurs on brittle materials only (there is no evidence of plastic deformation).",
    "The propagation direction of the fatigue crack coincides with the direction of application of the tensile stress that opens it.",
    "The unstable crack propagation is further accelerated by the assistance of fatigue (cyclic loading).",
    "The fatigue test determines the stresses that a sample of a material, with standardized dimensions, can withstand for a certain number of cycles."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An advantage of the ferrite stabilizer niobium vs titanium, used in filler metals, is that:",
    answers: ["its loses when being transferred through the arc is lower compared to titanium.",
    "though its through the arc transfer ratio is equal to that of titanium, niobium has a positive effect on penetration.",
    "though its through the arc transfer ratio is equal to that of titanium, niobium has a positive effect on wetting phenomenon.",
    "though its through the arc transfer ratio is equal to that of titanium, niobium has a positive effect on grain structure of the fusion zone."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture mechanism:",
    answers: ["nucleation of one or more cracks;",
    "growth of internal stresses;",
    "growth of defects in metal;",
    "generation of a brittle microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture mechanism:",
    answers: ["stable crack growth;",
    "growth of internal stresses;",
    "growth of defects in metal;",
    "generation of a brittle microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture mechanism:",
    answers: ["unstable crack growth (final rupture);",
    "growth of internal stresses;",
    "growth of defects in metal;",
    "generation of a brittle microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When designing structures of aluminium and its alloys subjected to dynamic loading, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["only the strength of the deposited weld metal should be taken into consideration;",
    "undercutting, lack of root penetration, pre-existing cracks and other discontinuities in welded joints can accelerate the fatigue cracks generation when subjected to cyclic loading;",
    "in welded joints, the porosity level does not influence on the joint fatigue behaviour under cyclic or static loading;",
    "the type of the groove preparation affects the fatigue behaviour as it can induce porosity in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fatigue failure of a welded joint, which of the following is true?",
    answers: ["The peening technique, although costly, eliminates the risk of fatigue failure.",
    "The notch sensitivity can be evaluated as a function of the radius of rounding of the notch tip and the hardness of the material in the region.",
    "The concave shape of the fillet weld surface does not enhance fatigue resistance.",
    "A high reinforcement of the welded joint does not influence fatigue failure as it is not characterized as a notch."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the geometric coefficient of stress concentration (Stress Concentration Factor), it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The geometric coefficient of stress concentration takes into account the sensitivity of the material to the notch;",
    "It depends on the geometry of the part and the notch;",
    "In general, higher strength steels are less sensitive to notch than more ductile steels;",
    "Joints built of high-carbon steels present geometric coefficients of stress concentration higher than the same joints built of low-carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the geometric coefficient of stress concentration (Stress Concentration Factor), it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The geometric coefficient of stress concentration takes into account the sensitivity of the material to the notch;",
    "Its values can be obtained in several ways, such as the theory of Elasticity, for simple cases, or experimentally, applying, for example, Photoelasticity, among others;",
    "In general, higher strength steels are less sensitive to notch than more ductile steels;",
    "Joints built of high-carbon steels present geometric coefficients of stress concentration higher than the same joints built of low-carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the geometric coefficient of stress concentration (Stress Concentration Factor), it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The geometric coefficient of stress concentration takes into account the sensitivity of the material to the notch;",
    "It can be obtained by applying the finite element method;",
    "In general, higher strength steels are less sensitive to notch than more ductile steels;",
    "Joints built of high-carbon steels present geometric coefficients of stress concentration higher than the same joints built of low-carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the stress relation between the longitudinal and the circumferential welds in a pressure vessel?",
    answers: ["Both longitudinal and circumferential welds are stressed equally.",
    "Circumferential welds have higher stresses, but only for large wall thicknesses.",
    "The longitudinal weld is stressed less than the circumferential one.",
    "The longitudinal weld is stressed twice more than the circumferential one."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The welded joint anisotropy means that:",
    answers: ["the base metal and the weld metal have different chemical composition;",
    "the base metal and the weld metal are characterized by different mechanical properties;",
    "the weld mechanical properties depend on the directions;",
    "the longitudinal and transversal dimensions of welds are different."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What can you say about the loading type of a dynamically loaded component if the stress ratio R is +0.33 and the minimum stress value is -50 MPa?",
    answers: ["The component is under pulsating compressive load. ",
    "The component is under pulsating tensile load. ",
    "The component is loaded by predominantly alternating tensile stresses (by 33%).",
    "The component is loaded by predominantly alternating compressive stresses (by 33%)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following characteristics is actually shown by aluminium alloys?",
    answers: ["Yield and tensile strengths are always much lower than those shown by steel grades commonly used in industrial applications.",
    "Mechanical properties in HAZ are substantially unaffected by welding operations.",
    "They generally guarantee good corrosion resistance, reduction in weight of structural elements, significant toughness even at very low temperatures.",
    "\"Their \"\"ductile-to-brittle\"\" transition lowers along with the reduction in temperature.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following characteristics is actually shown by aluminium alloys?",
    answers: ["Yield and tensile strengths are always much lower than those shown by steel grades commonly used in industrial applications.",
    "Mechanical properties in HAZ are substantially unaffected by welding operations.",
    "Material ductility is generally influenced by the treatment (ageing and/or hardening) the alloy has been subjected to.",
    "\"Their \"\"ductile-to-brittle\"\" transition lowers along with the reduction in temperature.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct for a dynamically loaded steel structure?",
    answers: ["Little weld cracks are admissible.",
    "No residual stresses are admitted, stress relieving is obligatory.",
    "Filet welds with concaves beads are always acceptable.",
    "A limited number of gas pores may be admissible."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Among different types of loading that a welded joint can be subjected to, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Dynamic loads are not allowed on fillet welds as they are partial penetration welds.",
    "Toughness requirements are especially important for high temperature applications.",
    "Stress concentrations are not a concern in welding, as design standards do not clearly establish a multiplier factor for each type of concentrator.",
    "In welding, there is great concern with shear stresses and, therefore, welds between bars and plates are normally dimensioned considering that this type of stress is predominant."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of using X-Ray inspection compared to Gamma-Ray inspection?",
    answers: ["X-ray inspection equipment is generally more portable.",
    "It is easier to control exposure using an X-ray machine than using radioisotopes.",
    "Nowadays, X-ray tubes are quite small in size, which makes it possible to easily take them to the materials to be tested.",
    "Gamma rays are much more dangerous to human health than X-rays."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of using X-Ray inspection compared to Gamma-Ray inspection?",
    answers: ["X-ray inspection equipment is generally more portable.",
    "It is easier to control exposure using an X-ray machine than using radioisotopes.",
    "Nowadays, X-ray tubes are quite small in size, which makes it possible to easily take them to the materials to be tested.",
    "The use of X-ray inspection offers superior quality of radiographs, especially for small thicknesses (up to 5 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of using X-Ray inspection compared to Gamma-Ray inspection?",
    answers: ["X-ray inspection equipment is generally more portable.",
    "It is easier to control exposure using an X-ray machine than using radioisotopes.",
    "Nowadays, X-ray tubes are quite small in size, which makes it possible to easily take them to the materials to be tested.",
    "The radiation energy of the X-ray machine is variable and can be adjusted to a variety of materials and thicknesses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of using X-Ray inspection compared to Gamma-Ray inspection?",
    answers: ["X-ray inspection equipment is generally more portable.",
    "It is easier to control exposure using an X-ray machine than using radioisotopes.",
    "Nowadays, X-ray tubes are quite small in size, which makes it possible to easily take them to the materials to be tested.",
    "Due to their limited useful lifespan, new isotopes have to be purchased on a regular basis so that the operating costs may exceed those of an X-ray source."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of using Gamma-Ray inspection (Gamma Radiography Testing) compared to X-Ray inspection?",
    answers: ["It is easier to protect against radiation (just always store the isotope inside the shielding box).",
    "The radiation energy of each isotope is different, so it is very easy to adapt the gamma ray source to given conditions by just substituting one isotope for another.",
    "Maintenance of radioisotopes is easier and cheaper than X-ray machines.",
    "Gamma rays are much less dangerous to human health than X-rays."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the use of X-ray inspection and Gamma Radiography Testing it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Generally, industrial X-ray radiography is preferred for small thicknesses, while Gamma Radiography Testing is chosen for greater thicknesses.",
    "Due to the danger that an isotope poses to human health, in most cases, the materials to be tested are taken to it, not the other way around an isotope is taken to the materials.",
    "Nowadays, X-ray tubes are quite small in size, what makes it possible to easily take them to the materials to be tested.",
    "Modern X-ray inspection equipment is generally more portable than isotope transport lead shielded box."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["perform, control or monitor a welding operation.",
    "supervise the activities of the IWI-B and IWI-S level inspectors.",
    "review welding construction contract requirements.",
    "specify, develop, evaluate, validate and manage working instructions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["carry out the organization of welding operations.",
    "develop and provide instructions to IWI-B and IWI-S level inspectors.",
    "perform technical review of the welding construction.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["monitor and implement the manufacturing plan.",
    "act as a technical expert for the Inspection function.",
    "specify, supervise and manage welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "understand, implement, supervise and monitor heat treatments."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["specify, develop, validate and manage the manufacturing plan.",
    "develop, comment and review Quality Control Plans and Inspection Testing Plans for applications not covered by product standards, codes, specifications, drawings and regulatory requirements.",
    "specify, supervise and manage welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "supervise the implementation and to monitor subcontracting activities."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["understand and implement work instructions.",
    "manage the whole of the Welding Inspection activities.",
    "calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "understand and supervise the proper use of equipment and means needed for the construction."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"As a welding inspector of IWI-C level you should be able to: ",
    answers: ["carry out the organization of welding operations.",
    "manage inspection activities for non-conventional applications with reference to materials, processes, and advanced destructive testing and NDT techniques.",
    "implement, monitor and control corrective actions to solve welded construction non-conformances.",
    "supervise implementation and monitor subcontracting activities."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is meant by an elliptical radiograph?",
    answers: ["Special test pieces with an elliptical form are tested.",
    "Oblique radiograph of tubes < 100 mm - the film is positioned planar under the tube.",
    "Oblique radiograph of the tube - film is positioned around the tube.",
    "Oblique radiograph of plates thickness > 10 mm - the film is positioned planar under the plate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The penetrating power of X-rays from an X-ray tube is determined by:",
    answers: ["The difference in voltage between the cathode and the anode.",
    "The tube current (mA).",
    "The distance between the cathode and the anode.",
    "The beam angle."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to most standards, the technical documentation of the qualification of a WPS should contain:",
    answers: ["the signature of the welder who participated in the qualification tests;",
    "the signature of the welder's immediate supervisor who participated in the qualification tests;",
    "the signature of a welding inspector qualified according to an appropriate standard, which may be from the same company;",
    "the signature of a representative of an independent classification society."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "It is applied, in most cases, to carbon steels and to a lesser extent to stainless steels, as ultrasound waves propagate well in ferrite, but in austenite they undergo strong attenuation, scattering and refraction."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "One of the disadvantages of this method is that it cannot be applied to the detection of discontinuities close to the surface (less than 2 – 3 mm of the depth), as the “dead zone”, existing in the instrument screen, prevents a clear response."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "Non-ferrous materials are difficult to examine by ultrasonic testing and special procedures are required."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "It can be applied to metallic and non-metallic materials."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "There is no need to stop other shop activities when this NDT method is being applied because it does not require strict security requirements."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "Allows to locate and dimension discontinuities with high precision."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "It can be performed in joints of complex geometry, such as nodes in tubular structures."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "It is a faster test than radiography."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "It does not apply to parts whose shape, geometry and surface roughness prevent the perfect coupling of the transducer head to the part."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "The coarse grain of certain base and weld metals (particularly nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steel) can scatter sound and cause false signals."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "The root reinforcement and backings can cause false indications."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "Ultrasonic testing defectoscopists require more training and experience to be qualified than other non-destructive testing defectoscopists."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "The best discontinuity detection depends on its orientation in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say about the applicability of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["It cannot be applied to large thickness carbon steel, due to the ultrasonic signal attenuation;",
    "Requires little theoretical knowledge on the part of the inspector;",
    "Ultrasonic equipment is not very portable (screen, ultrasound transducers, cables, ...), but it is rather cheap;",
    "Identifying the type of discontinuity requires a great deal of training and experience, but even then, it is not completely safe."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which non-destructive testing is based on the evaluation of the AC coil impedance?",
    answers: ["Eddy current test.",
    "Magnetic particle testing (PM).",
    "Radiographic Test.",
    "Ultrasonic Testing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which non-destructive testing uses changes in the electrical conductivity of the workpiece metal as an index of the presence of discontinuities?",
    answers: ["Eddy current test.",
    "Magnetic particle testing (PM).",
    "Radiographic Test.",
    "Ultrasonic Testing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In which non-destructive testing is an AC coil used?",
    answers: ["Inspection by eddy currents.",
    "LP (Liquid Penetrant).",
    "Radiographic Test.",
    "Ultrasonic Testing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following non-destructive tests would provide the best results in measuring the hardened surface layer depth on a surface hardened part?",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic immersion testing using a low frequency probe.",
    "Gamma ray inspection using the Cobalt 60 isotope.",
    "Eddy current test.",
    "Magnetic particle testing (PM)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the ultrasonic testing, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["In general, the operating frequency of the transducers starts at 20 kHz, because above this frequency the human being cannot hear.",
    "Calibration of the thickness gauge should be done using Step Wedges with thickness ranges close to the part to be inspected.",
    "It is not possible to be used in the automobile industry, due to the small sheet thicknesses used.",
    "Cannot be used on non-metallic materials."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the ultrasonic testing, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["In general, the operating frequency of the transducers starts at 20 kHz, because above this frequency the human being cannot hear.",
    "A 50% drop in signal amplitude represents a gain of 6 dB.",
    "It is not possible to be used in the automobile industry, due to the small sheet thicknesses used.",
    "Cannot be used on non-metallic materials."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"}]
    
    ;